Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
集中できてないな　まだ体が迷っているんだ
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
震えていたんじゃ　コントロールしたってブレるんだ
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
ツキ
太陽も勝負運もなんも完全にこっち向いていないが
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
「やるしかないんだ」
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
言い聞かせるようにそうつぶやいた
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
状況は悪いが　ただ逃げ出すんじゃ根性ないなぁ
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
展望はないが　度胸でクリアするしかないや
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
衝動は抑えたままターゲットとの間隔探れ
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
必要なもんは勝つプライド
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
味わうのは勝利の美酒か
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
それとも敗北の苦汁か
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
そう　すべては2つに1つ
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
操りたい運命の糸
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
絶好のゴールデンタイム　この手で掴め
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
渾身のポーカーフェイス　キメて仕掛けるよ
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
イリュージョンの世界へ引きずり込んで
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
際限無いプレッシャーゲーム　スルリと抜けて
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
栄光のボーダーライン　飛び越えるために
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
ハウメニー？　どれくらいの代償がいる？
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
手放したくないもんはどれ？
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
Who in the world are those guys?
なんです　あいつら
They're Kimblee's men, dispatched from the Central Army. Supposedly "bodyguards" for the Rockbell girl.
ロックベル嬢の護衛という名目で
中央軍から派遣されてきた　キンブリーの部下たちだ
What the hell are you planning to do at Briggs, Kimblee?
このブリッグズで何をする気だ　キンブリー
You should have told me if you were coming north.
北に行くならそう一言言いなさいよ
I didn't have time. I was in a rush.
しょうがねぇだろ　急ぎだったんだから
You guys are always  in a rush!
あんたたちはいっつも急ぎでしょ
Why were you locked up, anyway?
だいたい　なんで牢に入ってんの
It was just a misunderstanding.
単なる手違いですよ
They'll be set free soon enough.
すぐに出られます
I'll go through the formalities later.
後で手続きをしておきますよ
Thank you, Mr. Kimblee.
ありがとう　キンブリーさん
Please look after these blockheads for me.
こいつらのこと　よろしくお願いしますね
Of course.
ええ
Hey. Don't trust Kimblee too much.
おい　あんまりキンブリーを信用すんなよ
Why? He's a nice man.
なんで　いい人だよ
Ms. Rockbell.
ロックベルさん
Your parents were the doctors who lost their lives at Ishbal, were they not?
あなたのご両親は
イシュヴァールで命を落とされたお医者様ですね
Yes.
はい
As I thought.
やはり
It was my unit who recovered their bodies.
遺体を収容したのは私の部隊です
えっ
We were a second too late.
When we arrived at the scene, they were already...
あと一歩間に合わず
私たちが現場に着いた時にはすでに
I see...
そうですか
They obeyed the ethics of medicine and
stuck to their convictions until the very end.
医の倫理に従い　最後まで意志を貫き通す
I admire them from the bottom of my heart.
心から敬服します
I wish I could have met them while they were still with us.
ご存命のうちにお会いしたかった
They kept a picture that was taken with an adorable little girl.
かわいらしい娘さんと一緒に写った写真を
大切そうに持っておられました
Your existence must have been what drove them onwards.
あなたの存在が心の支えだったのでしょう
It's a pleasure to make your acquaintance, Miss Winry Rockbell.
お会いできて光栄です　ウィンリィ·ロックベルさん
Hey! Do you know what he did at Ishbal?!
お前　あいつがイシュヴァールで何をやったか
I've only heard the true stories about Ishbal from the Lieutenant.
オレはまだ
中尉の話でしかイシュヴァールのこと知らないんだ
From the Lieutenant...
中尉の話
You're in love with Winry, aren't you?
大好きなんでしょ　ウィンリィちゃんのこと
Calm down!
落ち着け　何か違うこと
Just... Just think about something else, Ed!
違うこと考えるんだ　オレ
Hydrogen, helium, lithium, beryllium...
水素 ヘリウム リチウム ベリリウム 炭素 窒素 酸素
...carbon, nitrogen, oxygen, sulfur...
E-Ed?
エ　エド
アルミニウム　ケイ素　リン　クロム　マンガン
...aluminum, silicon, phosphorus, chromium, manganese, iron...
鉄　コバルト　ニッケル…
...cobalt, nickel...
Why did I fall for a weirdo like him?
なんで　こんな変なのに惚れたんだろう
Did you say something?
あっ　なんか言ったか
N-Nothing!
なんでもないわよ
Oww!
痛ぇ
てっ　てめぇ
D-Damn you, I told you to let me know before you join the nerves!
神経繋ぐ時は言えっつってんだろ
Yeah, whatever. Now for your leg.
はいはい　次足ね
It's so light!
軽っ　こんなんで強度大丈夫なのか
Doesn't its durability suffer if you make it so light?
If you look at the big picture, it's less durable than it used to be, but the key points have been reinforced.
うん　前のより全体の強度は落ちるけど
要所要所は強化してあるよ
Why are you out of your cell?
貴様　なんで牢を出ている
Dunno.
さあね　これが国家錬金術師の力ってやつ
I guess you can think of it as
my capability as a State Alchemist.
You finally switched to a northern type?
今ごろ寒冷地用に換装か
Looks like you've got some changes, too.
そちらさんも
This suits me the best!
やはりこれが一番しっくりくる
うっは　軽戦闘用機械鎧Ｍ１９１０
Light-weight combat automail, M-1910!
What?! The tip of your nails are reinforced!
爪の先だけ強化してある　もしかしてダイヤ素材
Don't tell me it's made out of diamond?!
That's right. It's a Neo M-1910, Mad Bear G!
おう　Ｍ１９１０改　マッドベアＧだ
うわぁ
Hey! Want me to equip you with something like this, Ed?!
ちょっと　エドもこういうの付けない
No thanks!
断る
So who is this pretty gal?
おい誰だ　このかわいい娘は
She's my mechanic.
オレの整備士
What the hell was that for?!
何すんだよ
It kind of pissed me off.
なんかむかついた
What an ass...
ひっでぇな
That's the first time I've actually seen a northern automail!
初めて見た北国用　感激だな
I'm so happy!
Really?
そうか　なんならオレの仕事場見る
Then do you want to look around my workplace?
Yes! Yes, I'd love to!
見る　見る　見ます
Hey!
おい
What?
何よ
W-Well...
あっ　いや
Don't get too carried away and walk around all over the place.
あんまり浮かれて
その辺うろちょろすんじゃねぇぞ
砦の中　いろいろ危ねぇから
It's kind of dangerous around here. In a lot of ways.
Gotcha. I won't. Thanks for the warning.
うん　分かった
Thanks for allowing me to look around!
よろしくお願いします
This one right here is pretty rare.
これなんか珍しいよ
Wow! This is amazing! Isn't this a Crocodile?!
うわ　すごい
クロコダイルですよね
She's so spirited about her work, just like how her parents were.
ご両親に似て仕事熱心ですね
Yeah, that's right.
The thing really setting this apart from others is...
こいつの特徴は
...it was designed with the material's expansion rate in mind.
材質の膨張率を考慮して設計した
Well, since your limbs are good to go...
さて　機械鎧の換装も無事に済んだことですし
...let's get down to business...
仕事の話をしましょう　鋼の錬金術師殿
...Mr. Fullmetal Alchemist.
So...
あの　なんで僕は出してくれないのかな
...why can't I  be let out?
Mr. Kimblee's orders.
キンブリー様の命令だ
We've been told to only release the Fullmetal Alchemist for now.
今は鋼の錬金術師殿だけ出すように言われている
貴様はおとなしく…
Kimblee's men...
キンブリーの部下
They thought this through, not letting us work together.
一緒に行動させないなんて　徹底してるな
They've also taken the effort to bring Winry here to show us that she's in their hands.
わざわざウィンリィを連れてきて
我々の手の内だって強調してるし
I guess that shows how cautious they are about us.
それだけ　僕たちのことを警戒してるってことか
I can't rush this. I have to wait for the right chance.
焦っちゃダメだ　チャンスを待つんだ
The advance unit only brought enough food for three days.
先遣隊が持っていった食料は３日分
It's already been a week since they left.
もう１週間も経っています
They could be on the verge of starvation.
ギリギリだな
I'm also worried about their sanity.
精神面も心配です
Being in complete darkness for an entire week is...
暗闇で１週間となると
Let us put our trust in their minds.
彼らの精神力を信じよう
General, there's no knowing what could happen down there.
閣下　穴の奥で何が起こるか予測できません
If we don't return in twenty-four hours, please seal this entrance.
２４時間経っても戻らなかった時は
穴を塞いでください
Understood.
分かった　そうしよう
Since you're all here, I have something to tell you.
今のうちに皆に言っておく
The murder of Lieutenant General Raven was my decision and act, alone.
レイブン中将の件は私が個人的にやったことだ
You all didn't see or hear anything.
諸君らは何も見なかったし　聞かなかった
If word gets out, blame everything on me.
事が露見した場合は
私にすべての責任を吹っかけろ
Aye, ma'am.
アイ　マム
Let's get moving.
行くぞ
I see. Looks like things are starting to get hectic up north.
なるほど　随分北も物騒になってきたようだな
Yeah. We're going to have to start taking the initiative from now on.
ああ　これからは先手先手を取らないとね
Briggs is staffed with men well-versed in defense.
ブリッグズは守りに長けた集団
Only one who excels in both offense and defense can snatch a victory by making the first move.
先手必勝は攻守共に秀でた者だからできること
Which is why Madam Olivier believes that working with the
Eastern Army, well-versed in offensive tactics, is the best option.
だから　攻めに長けた東方軍と組むのが最善
というのがオリヴィエ様の考えだよ
It's an honor to be selected as a partner for her tag team.
タッグの相手に選んでいただけるとは光栄だ
I think you have it wrong.
いいや　オリヴィエ様が欲しいのは東方軍の力だから
She said she just wants the power of the Eastern Army, and she'd rather you take a hike.
マスタングはむしろ消えろってさ
Oh, okay...
ああ　そう
Let me ask you this, though. What if I sold this information to the Führer President for my own gain?
一つ聞くが
もし私が保身のために
この情報を大総統に売ったらどうする
"Impossible. Mustang wouldn't do that," so she says.
ありえない　マスタングはそういう男ではないってね
That'll be 35,000 cenz.
ほれ　３万５０００センズ
It's an honor.
光栄だね
Madam, who are you exactly?
ご婦人　あなたは
Just a florist who's worked with the Armstrongs for generations.
アームストロング家に代々仕えし
花屋のおばちゃんさ
Hughes, it seems the people who truly understand and support you are the ones who fought beside you in a war.
ヒューズよ
理解して支えてくれる人間ってのは
結局のところ
共に戦ったことのある戦友から出てくるものなんだな
Now...
さて
What to do with these flowers...
この花　どうしよう
What in the world?
（何あれ　変な人ね）
What a weirdo.
Oh, god! He's looking this way!
（やだ　こっち見てる）
This is horrible...
ひでぇな
It's the same as Smith's arm.
スミスの腕と同じだ
Even metal has been cut up.
金属までさっくりやられてる
Stay on your toes. The enemy may still be around.
気をつけろ
敵がいるかもしれん
There's someone there!
誰かいるぞ
Don't worry.
大丈夫だ
Look, it's me.
分かるか　オレだ
L-Lieutenant Henshel?
ヘ　ヘンシェル少尉
Thank god you're alive.
よく生きててくれた
Is it just the two of you?
お前たちだけか
What about the others?
ほかは
ほっ　ほかは皆　バラバラに
E-Everyone else is in... p-pieces!
We... We have to get out of here quickly!
早く　早くここを出ないと
That thing will come back!
あれが来る
"That thing"?
あれ
あ　明かりはダメだ
D-Don't turn on the lights!
The shadow... The shadow will come back!
影が　影が来る
Calm down!
落ち着け　おい
Hey!
影
Hey! Get a hold of yourself!
おい　しっかりしろ
The shadow!
影が
Can you stand?
立てるか
Let's go.
行くぞ
Carry as many men as you can.
背負えるだけ背負っていけ
I apologize for visiting so late at night.
夜分に失礼いたします
I've come to deliver an urgent document to the Führer President.
閣下に急ぎの書類を届けに参りました
Oh, my. I'm sorry.
あらまあ
ごめんなさい　あの人今出かけてるのよ
He's not at home right now.
I'd like him to look through these by tomorrow.
明日までに目を通しておいていただきたいのですが
By tomorrow, right? I'll let him know.
明日までね
分かりました　お預かりします
Thank you very mu-
では　よろしくお願い
You were still awake, Selim?
セリム　まだ起きてたの
Yes. I heard the door open,
so I thought Father might have returned.
はい　玄関の音がしたから
お義父さんが帰って来たのかと
This is Lieutenant Hawkeye.
この方はホークアイ中尉よ
Good evening, Miss Hawkeye.
こんばんは　ホークアイさん
It's a pleasure to meet you.
はじめまして
Do you always work such late hours?
こんな時間までお仕事なんですか
That's right. I've come to deliver a document to your father.
はい　閣下に書類を届けに来ました
I apologize for waking you.
お休みのところ起こしてしまって　申し訳ありません
Now, Selim. You must sleep now, or you'll have a difficult time waking up tomorrow.
さあ　セリム様
お休みにならないと　明日寝坊してしまいますよ
Okay.
はい
He seems like a bright boy.
聡明なご子息ですね
Yes, we're very proud of him.
そうでしょう　自慢の息子よ
You could call me an indulgent mother if he were my real child, but since he's an orphan, I can boast all I want.
実の子なら親バカと言われるけど
養子だから　遠慮なく自慢できるの
Well, he's distantly related to my husband, so it could be his blood that made him so wonderful.
まあ　ブラッドレイの遠縁の子だから
出来がいいのは　あの人の血筋なのかもしれないわね
He's not related to you?
奥様の遠縁では
No.
いいえ
According to the Colonel, King Bradley was raised as a test subject since he was an infant and has no blood relatives.
大佐の話によると
キング·ブラッドレイは
幼少の頃から実験体として育てられ
天涯孤独の身　親戚など一人もいない
He shouldn't have any distant relatives.
And that feeling I sensed earlier...
それに　さっきのあの感覚
Just who is that boy?
あの子は…
気づいちゃいました
Oops, did you notice?
Oh, that mother of mine...
困りましたね
うちのお義母さん　おしゃべりが好きで
She just loves to talk.
I sensed a hint of bloodlust earlier.
さっき　一瞬奇妙な殺気を感じました
以前にもどこかで
I've felt the same sensation before...
And I just remembered where it was from.
けれど　はっきりと思い出しました
It's the same sensation I felt when a Homunculus by the name of Gluttony snuck up on me.
グラトニーという人造人間に
背後を取られたときの感覚です
Selim Bradley...
セリム·ブラッドレイ
あなたは一体何者ですか
Just what are you?
You have quite the nerve to ask me that in this situation, Lieutenant Hawkeye.
この状況で私の正体を聞くとは
大した度胸ですね　ホークアイ中尉
It's also smart of you not to pull out your gun, which you're so skilled with.
得意の銃を抜かないのもよい判断です
You can't defeat me.
あなたでは私に勝てません
Are you also a Homunculus, like Gluttony?
あなたもグラトニーと同じ人造人間
No, I sense a power that can hardly be compared to that of Gluttony's.
いいえ　グラトニーとは比べものにならない
プレッシャーを感じるわね
I'd be offended if you put me on the same level as him.
ヤツと同じレベルだと思われるのは　心外です
My name is Pride. The First Homunculus.
私の名は　プライド
始まりの人造人間
The First Homunculus, you say?
始まりの人造人間と言ったわね
What do you mean by that?
それはどういう意味
Exactly as the words mean.
言葉どおりです
So you're planning on gathering as much information as you can, huh?
少しでも情報を引き出そうってわけですか
You're really a brave one.
本当に度胸がありますね
What do you say you join us?
あなた　こちらの仲間になりませんか
Join you?
仲間　駒が欲しいだけでしょう
You just want another pawn, don't you?
I see. That's a shame.
そうですか　残念です
じゃあ
In that case...
Will you cut the empty threats already?
無駄な脅しはやめてくれないかしら
There's no benefit in killing a hostage, is there?
人質を殺しては意味がないでしょ
I'm amazed you saw through it.
よく分かってますね
However, Lieutenant Hawkeye...
でもホークアイ中尉
I'll always be watching you from your shadows.
私はいつでも　あなたの影から見ていますからね
Work?
仕事だと
Yes, as a State Alchemist.
ええ　国家錬金術師として
You have three tasks from the Führer President.
大総統からの指示は三つ
Your first task is to search for Scar. All you have to do is find him.
まず一つ目　スカーの捜索
見つけるだけです
I'll take care of him after that.
後始末は私の仕事
Your second task is to look for Doctor Marcoh, who is presumed to be escaping alongside Scar.
二つ目　同じくスカーと逃げている可能性がある
ドクター·マルコーの捜索
Doctor Marcoh is with Scar?
ドクター·マルコーがスカーと
これも見つけたら後は私の仕事
Just like with your previous task,
after you find him, I'll take care of the rest.
Then, your third task is to carve a bloody crest into Briggs.
そして三つ目は
このブリッグズに血の紋を刻む
Carve a bloody crest?
血の紋を刻む
イシュヴァールと同じです
It's the same as Ishbal.
Slaughtering humans and carving a symbol of hatred and sorrow into the land.
人々を殺め　憎悪と悲しみをこの地に刻む
There's no way I could...
んなことできるわけ
You became a dog of the military without the resolve to kill?
人を殺す覚悟もなく軍の狗になったのですか
With the resolve not  to kill.
殺さねぇ覚悟だ
With a resolve not to kill...
殺さない覚悟…　ふむ
That can also be true, if you stick with it.
それもまた貫き通せば真理
Are you lending them a hand,
knowing what those guys are up to?
あんた　連中がやろうとしてること
分かってて協力してんのか　ヤツらは…
They're-
I want to see how the world will change.
世界の変わるさまを見てみたい
はあ
Resolve pitted against resolve.
覚悟と覚悟　意思と意思
Will clashing against will.
Life against life.
命と命　人間と人造人間
And humans against the Homunculi.
Who will win? Which will the world choose as the victor?
どちらが勝つのか　世界が何を選ぶのか
If humans are defeated by Homunculi, those who claim to be an evolved form of them, it's truly a historical moment.
進化した人間を名乗る人造人間に
人間が滅ぼされるとしたら
それこそ歴史的瞬間
I just want to live to see that happen.
私はそれを見届けたいだけです
Why are you, a human, working with the Homunculi?
なんで人間であるあんたが人造人間側に付いてるんだ
Because they'll let me use my alchemy as I please.
私の錬金術を遠慮なく使わせてくれるからですよ
You're insane.
まともじゃねぇな
I know that I'm not normal.
自分が異端であることは知っています
But if someone like me survives this,
then it means the world's selected me.
しかし　私のような者が生き残れば
それは世界が私を選んだということ
The survivors...
生き残りをまさに存在を懸けた闘い
It's a battle for existence.
How worthwhile.
こんなやりがいのある人生はありませんよ
I can't understand you.
オレには分かんねぇよ
Oh, what a shame.
おや　残念
I always thought all alchemists were selfish.
錬金術師とは
皆自己中心的なものと思っていたのですがね
Let me try appealing to your selfish side.
では
あなたの自己中心的な部分に語りかけるとしましょう
Here's something you want more than anything in the world.
のどから手が出るほど欲しいはずです
If you accept the job, it's yours.
仕事を引き受けるなら　差し上げましょう
A philosopher's stone!
賢者の石
Let me talk it over with Al and Winry.
アルとウィンリィに話をさせてくれ
With Miss Winry, too?
ウィンリィさんにも
I haven't told her anything.
あいつには何も言ってねぇんだ
Whatever job I may have to do,
I don't want to lie to her and betray her.
どんな仕事するにしろ
嘘をついて裏切りたくねぇ
いいでしょう
Very well.
I'll be monitoring you, so you don't tell her anything she doesn't need to know.
余計なことはしゃべらないよう　同席させてもらいます
Winry.
ウィンリィ　今のお前は人質状態だ
You're currently being kept as a hostage.
What? What do you mean?
何それ
どういうこと　冗談
Is this a joke?
Listen up.
いいか　オレは人間兵器として仕事しろって
I've been instructed by the higher-ups to do my duty as a human weapon.
上から命令されている
So I may have to be party to mass murder.
だから　大量殺人に手を貸すことになるかもしれない
What?!
えっ　そんなの断れば
But can't you just refuse...
Oh, so that's why I'm...
あっ　それで私が
やだ　私
No... I'm being a burden to you two.
あんたたちの足かせになってる
I won't cry!
泣かないよ　ごめん
I'm sorry.
I'm just mad at myself for being so happy-go-lucky.
能天気だった自分に腹が立つ
Why is this...
なんで　あんたたちは元の体に戻りたいだけなのに
You two just want to get your bodies back...
About that...
それなんだが　作戦に協力すれば賢者の石がもらえる
They'll give us a philosopher's stone if I help them.
えっ　石って　でも
What? A stone?
But...
Kimblee has one.
キンブリーが持ってる
Yeah, but those stones are made of...
そうじゃなくて　石の材料は
I know that!
分かってる
Do whatever you want, geez...
勝手にしなよ　もう
ああ
That's the plan.
I've decided to take the job.
決まりだ　仕事受けるぜ
Let me look for Scar first.
まずスカーの捜索からやらせてくれ
Oh? Why is that?
ほう　なぜです
Scar killed Winry's parents.
スカーはウィンリィの両親を殺した
I want to avenge them.
敵を討ちたい
I see. Fair enough.
なるほど　分かりました
And I'll be taking Al with me.
それと　アルも一緒に連れてく
Since he's in that state, Scar can't use his destruction techniques on him.
あいつあのナリだから
スカーの人体破壊が効かねぇんだ
Oh, how convenient.
ほう　それは便利な
Is it really okay, Al?
アル　いいの
賢者の石って　沢山の人の命を犠牲にして作られたんだ
A philosopher's stone is made by sacrificing the lives of many people.
はっ
大丈夫
Don't worry.
Brother isn't planning to use it at all.
兄さんはそんなものを使うつもりはないよ
We're thinking that there may be a way to get
our bodies back by using Eastern Alchemy from Xing.
僕らは今　シンの錬丹術に
元の体に戻る可能性を探っているんだ
And a little girl who can use
Eastern Alchemy is supposedly with Scar.
その錬丹術使いの女の子が
スカーと行動を共にしているらしい
So he's making it look like he's going after Scar, but his plan is to get in touch with that girl?
じゃあ　スカーを追うと見せかけてその女の子を
うん　多分ね
That's my guess.
I see.
そっか
だったら私も　もっともらしい理由考えなきゃね
Then I'd better think up a good reason, too.
Huh?
えっ
We're going to head to the location Scar was last sighted.
まず　スカーが最後に目撃された場所に向かう
Sounds good.
いいでしょう
Okay, scoot in!
はい　ちょっとそこ詰めて
Al, scoot over some more!
アル　もう少しそっち詰めて
えっ
Hey, what the heck?!
お前　なんで
Ms. Winry, please wait at the fortress.
ウィンリィさん 砦で待っていてください
This isn't a game.
遊びではないんですよ
I know that!
分かってます
But I just fixed up his automail, right?
でも　機械鎧を替えたでしょ
It would be bad if it stopped working all of a sudden, so I should go along in case maintenance is needed.
もし作動不良とかあったら困るし
メンテナンスについていかないと
If something were to happen, it would hurt the proud name of the Rockbells!
何かあったら　ロックベルの名に傷が付いちゃうもの
You're really into your work, aren't you?
お前　相変わらず仕事熱心だな
You workaholic.
仕事バカ
Of course I'm into it!
当たり前でしょ
うちはひいじいちゃんの代から信用第一でやってる
We've been in business since my great-grandfather's generation!
Okay. Very well.
いいでしょう　分かりました
I know that!
知ってるよ　機械オタ一家
I'll allow it.
同行を許しましょう
You're from a family of machine freaks.
機械オタ結構
I don't care if you call me a machine freak!
何が起こるか分かんねぇぞ
There's no knowing what will happen.
I know.
うん
でも　待ってるだけなんてもうイヤ
But I'm sick of sitting and waiting for something to happen.
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
朝日が昇るまで語り合ったね
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
夕陽が沈むまでつないだ手
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
こうやって明日も明後日も共に歩もう光と影
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
寂しげに見つめる街の中で
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
温もりはひとりじゃ見つからなくて
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
愛がこんなに強さになること
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
知ったんだ　キミに出逢えてはじめて
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
一人じゃ眠れない　夢は見れないから
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
どんな不安も届かないところへ
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
星のない夜も照らし続けよう
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
何処までも行けるキミとなら
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
一人じゃ歩けない道も二人なら
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
鼻歌歌いながら歩けるんだ
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
キミがいれば幸せ
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
寒風吹き荒れる炭鉱の町を舞台に
An all-out war between chimeras and humans takes place in a mining town where the piercing wind blows.
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
合成獣と人間の総力戦が繰り広げられる
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
油断をするな　死力を尽くせ
Don't let down your guard. Give it your best.
激戦の果てに訪れる意外な結末とは
What is the strange aftermath brought forth by the fierce battle?
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第三十八話　バズクールの激闘
Episode 38, Conflict at Baschool.
Humans let down their guard in their moments of victory.
勝利の瞬間　人は無防備になる